Finding Aid for Benjamin C. Stanczyk papers, 1944-1975
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Benjamin C. Stanczyk papers 1944-1975
Stanczyk, Benjamin C. (Benjamin Conrad), 1915-
3 linear feet and 12 oversize volumes
85545 Aa 2; AC
Judge of Common Pleas. Correspondence and other materials relating to politics and to Polish-American interests.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Benjamin Stanczyk (donor no. 4196 )
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Benjamin C. Stanczyk was Judge of Common Pleas in Detroit, Michigan. He was active in Democratic Party affairs and in various Polish-American organizations.
The collection relates primarily to his interest in the Democratic Party in Michigan and to his involvement in Polish-American activities and organizations.
Subjects:
Democratic Party (Mich.); Detroit (Mich.); Judges--Michigan--Detroit.; Michigan--Politics and government--1946-1960.; Michigan--Politics and government--1961-1970.; Polish Americans--Michigan.; Michigan--Politics and government--1951-; Michigan--Politics and government--1837-1950.
Genre Terms:
Scrapbooks.
- Political papers / Polish-American interests
  - Correspondence, 1950-1964 (Box 1)
  - Miscellanea, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Notebook concerning arrangements for Pulaski Day Parade, 1956 (Box 1)
    (Stanczyk was executive secretary of the Central Citizens Committee which co-sponsored the parade with the Polish Legion of American Veterans)
  - Report of Citizens Income Tax Study Committee to the Common Council of the City of Detroit, 1961 (Box 1)
  - Notebooks of correspondence and memorabilia, 1 volume (Box 1)
  - Diary, 1944-1945 (Box 1)
  - Notebooks of correspondence and memorabilia, 18 volumes (Box 2)
  - Notebook of correspondence and memorabilia, 8 volumes (Box 3)
  - Captive Nations Committee, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Father Kern "Seamen Letter", 1973-1974 (Box 3)
  - Sixth Judicial Conference, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Pulaski Day, 1950s (Box 3)
  - College Papers, 1935-1936 (Box 3)
  - Hearing before the Senate Judiciary Committee, Sub-committee on Juvenile Delinquency, July 1967 (Box 3)
  - Select Committee on Firearms Control testimony on behalf of Michigan Antique Firearm Collectors, 1975 (Box 3)
  - Central Citizen's Committee, 1953, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Claims and Delivery Statute 4470, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Scrapbooks of correspondence, clippings, and memorabilia, 12 volumes (Volume 1)